What were you like as a teenager?
你十几岁时是什么样子？
I was a nightmare.
我那时候就是个噩梦。
I was rude to my parents, always stayed out late, never did my homework, hung out with the wrong people and made lots of bad decisions.
对父母很粗鲁，总在外待到很晚，从不做作业，和不三不四的人混在一起，还做了很多糟糕的决定。
Apparently, this is the age when teenagers are out of control and behave badly.
显然，人们认为这个年纪的青少年难以管教、行为不端。
Maybe, if you're a teenager now, you think this is unfair criticism or it's not your fault.
如果你现在是青少年，可能会觉得这种评价不公平，或者觉得这不是你的错。
Well, you might be right!
嗯，你或许是对的！
Experts have found that it's a teenager's brain that is to blame.
专家发现，问题可能出在青少年的大脑上。
Between the ages of approximately 13 to 19 - a period known as adolescence - the brain is still developing in areas that control behaviour.
在大约13到19岁（即青春期），大脑中控制行为的区域仍在发育。
This has an impact on learning and multitasking, stress and memory, sleep, addiction, and decision-making.
这会影响学习、多任务处理、压力与记忆、睡眠、成瘾以及决策能力。
For parents, these consequences often manifest themselves in a variety of behaviours that they may have previously blamed on hormones or just moodiness.
对父母来说，这些影响往往体现在各种行为上，而他们以前可能会将这些行为归咎于荷尔蒙或单纯的情绪化。
This is quite a new discovery, according to Professor Sarah-Jayne Blakemore, who, speaking on the BBC radio programme The Life Scientific, says "when I was at university, the dogma in the text books was that the vast majority of brain development goes on in the first few years of life and nothing much changes after mid-childhood.
萨拉-杰恩・布莱克莫尔教授在BBC广播节目《科学人生》中表示，这是一个相当新的发现。她说：“我上大学时，教科书中的信条是，大脑发育的绝大部分发生在生命的最初几年，童年中期之后就没什么变化了。
That dogma is completely false."
但这种教条完全是错误的。”
So our brains are still developing much later than was originally thought.
因此，我们的大脑发育时间比最初认为的要晚得多。
Is this the perfect excuse for teenagers to lounge around and not get their homework done on time?
这难道是青少年闲逛偷懒、不按时完成作业的完美借口吗？
Of course not!
当然不是！
According to Professor Sarah-Jayne Blakemore, it's to do with our prefrontal cortex – that's the part of our brain right at the front, just behind the forehead.
萨拉-杰恩・布莱克莫尔教授认为，这与我们的前额叶皮层有关——即大脑前端、前额后方的部分。
She says "it’s involved in a whole range of very high-level cognitive tasks such as decision making and planning - we know that this region is undergoing very very large amounts of development during the adolescent years".
她说：“它参与一系列非常高级的认知任务，比如决策和规划——我们知道这个区域很大部分在青少年时期正在发育。”
This is the part of the brain critically involved in planning, and, for a teenager, this hasn't developed yet.
这部分大脑对规划至关重要，而对青少年来说，它尚未发育成熟。
So getting organised to do their homework, for example, can come as a bit of a challenge.
因此，比如有条理地完成作业，对他们来说可能有点困难。
I wish I’d known about this because instead of telling my teacher I’d left my homework on the bus or that the dog had eaten it.
我真希望我以前就知道这一点，那样就不用跟老师说“作业落在公交车上了”或者“被狗吃了”。
Now I could say, "Sorry sir, my brain isn’t developed enough for the cognitive task of planning my homework".
现在我就可以说：“对不起，老师，我的大脑还没发育到能完成规划作业这种认知任务的程度。”